[MUSIC]
[음악]
So for that first review, they had product sentiment predicted as 1,
첫 리뷰의 상품 감성이 1이라고 예측했는데
let's take a look at that review.
리뷰를 보죠
So I'm gonna look at the giraffe_reviews.
giraffe_reviews를 봅니다
The first one is 0, the index 0, and let's look at the actual text of the review.
처음은 인덱스 0인데 실제 리뷰 텍스트를 보죠
Okay, I'm gonna read this to you a little bit.
조금 읽어드리죠
It says, Sophie, oh Sophie, your time has come.
소피, 오 소피 네 차례가 다가왔구나
My granddaughter, Violet is 5 months old and starting to teeth.
손녀 바이올렛이 5달이 돼서 이가 나기 시작했네
What a joy for little Sophie.
소피에게 이보다 더한 기쁨 있으랴
Little Sophie brings to Violet.
소피가 바이올렛에게 다가가네
Oh Violet really loves Sophie [SOUND].
오 바이올렛은 소피를 아주 좋아하네
Sophie is made of very pliable rubber that is sturdy but not tough.
소피는 고무가 유연하고 튼튼하지만 딱딱하지 않다네
And it's quite easy for Violet to twist all her positions and put it in her mouth.
바이올렛이 이리저리 뒤틀어서 입에 넣기 좋다네
Okay, that's the right positive review looks like.
긍정적인 리뷰라면 이럴 테지요
She write a poem about Sophie.
소피에 대해 완전 시를 썼습니다
Let's look at the second placed review here.
두 번째로 긍정적인 리뷰를 보죠
So tihs is the, for element 1, so it's the second element on the table.
방금 게 첫 번째였고 이제 표에서 두 번째입니다
And let's look at what that review looks like.
리뷰가 뭐라고 하는지 봅시다
And here's what it says, I'm not sure why Sophie is such a hit with the little ones,
소피가 애들한테 왜 이리 인기인지 모르겠지만
but my 7 month old baby girl is one of the adoring fans.
7달된 딸은 완전 팬이다
The rubber is softer and pleasant to handle.
고무는 부드럽고 다루기 편하다
My daughter enjoy chewing on it, [SOUND] on the legs, chewing on the legs,
딸은 다리나 머리에서 튀어나온 부분을
nubs of the head.
물어뜯기를 좋아한다
So these ears get chewed and so on.
귀 같은 걸 물어뜯곤 한다
[SOUND] She really loves it and she loves that squeaky, so
아이가 아주 좋아하네요
apparently it's a big hit.
삑삑 소리내는 것까지 히트상품인가 봅니다
So this is two positive reviews.
긍정적 리뷰 두 개를 살펴봤습니다
Now let me show you a little python trick which you can use to show
가장 부정적인 리뷰를 보는 파이썬의 요령을
the most negative reviews.
알려드리죠
So the most negative reviews are at the bottom of the table.
가장 부정적인 리뷰는 표 밑에 있습니다
So we could ask what is the length from the table and
표 길이를 보고
find the last element and so on.
마지막 원소를 찾는 방법으로 할 수 있겠죠
But with python, we can do this really easily.
하지만 파이썬에서는 더 간단합니다
So let me show you what's happening next.
곧바로 보여드리죠
Show most negative reviews.
가장 부정적인 리뷰 보여주기
So we can take this table and just index it with a negative number, minus 1.
이 표에서 음수인 -1을 인덱스로 씁니다
And what that does is it goes to the end of the table.
그러면 표 뒤에서부터 세게 됩니다
So minus one is the last element,
-1이면 마지막 원소
minus two is the second to last element, and so on.
-2이면 뒤에서 두 번째 원소입니다
So let's look at the most negative review for our giraffe.
기린에 대해 가장 부정적인 리뷰를 보도록 하죠
And I forgot to put a quote here, so let's just do that and execute.
여기 따옴표를 잊었네요 빨리 쓰고 실행합니다
Okay.
좋아요.
Here's a negative review about poor Sophie.
소피에 대해 부정적인 리뷰입니다
My son loved Sophie.
아들이 소피를 좋아했다
I bought one for every baby shower I've gone to.
그래서 베이비 샤워마다 사서 선물했다
Now, my daughter is 6 months old just today nearly choked on it.
그런데 오늘 6살된 딸이 목에 걸려 질식할 뻔했다
Now I'll never give it to her again.
다시는 가지고 놀게 하지 않을 생각이다
So the problem is this person's daughter is really scary,
문제는 이 사람 딸이 무섭게도 기린을
almost choked by trying to swallow this giraffe.
삼키려다 질식할 뻔했나 보네요
And so you see a negative review of somebody talking about how this giraffe,
이 귀여운 기린이 목에 걸리는 흉기가 된다는
which is a lovely chewing toy, is also a choking hazard.
부정적인 리뷰를 봤습니다
Let's look at the second most negative review.
두 번째로 부정적인 리뷰를 보죠
So again, giraffe and minus 2,
giraffe[-2]면
second most negative review and we'll take a quick look at it.
두 번째로 부정적인 리뷰입니다
So one thing that people don't like about it is it might be a choking hazard.
먼저는 목에 걸려서 싫다고 했죠
So let's see what this one says.
이 사람은 뭐라고 하는지 봅시다
This children's toy is nostalgic and very cute.
이 아기 장남감은 어릴 적을 떠올리게 하고 앙증맞다
That sounds pretty positive.
꽤 긍정적으로 들리네요
Even the second most negative review starts pretty positive.
두 번째로 부정적인 리뷰인데도 긍정적인 문장으로 시작합니다
However, the distinct rubber smell and very old odd taste.
하지만 고무 냄새가 코를 찌르고 맛은 이상하다
Yes, I tried it.
그래, 직접 물어뜯어봤다
So this person tried to chew his or her kid's toy.
애들 장난감을 물어뜯었나 보네요
That my baby did not enjoy.
아기가 별로 좋아하지 않았다
So apparently, the rubber smells and
보아하니 고무 냄새가 나는데
this person wasn't able to clean it.
지울 수가 없었나 봅니다
And the kid did not like it.
아기가 그걸 싫어했고요
And they overpaid for this toy.
쓸모없는 장난감에 돈을 썼습니다
So the second thing that people complain about is that this is a smelly toy.
이 사람은 냄새에 대해 항의하네요
Smells okay to me, but could be an issue.
저는 괜찮은 거 같은데 다른 사람은 싫어할지도 모르죠
Okay, so now in a few lines of code, we build a sentiment analysis.
지금까지 몇 줄로 감성 분석을 해봤습니다
A system that can actually look at reviews and really sort them and
리뷰를 기준으로 정렬해서
show really positive and negative aspects of this particular product.
상품의 긍정적, 부정적 측면을 보여주는 시스템이죠
[MUSIC]
[음악]